And this is where the
magic really happens.
If you look to your right.
you will see the office
of the man himself.
our host. Scotty Bristol.
He's probably in there right
now. going over material.
preparing for tonight's show.
which tapes in a few hours.
What do you say we
say a quick hello?
[chuckles]
Actually. I-I think I'll
keep my job instead.
A-And right next door
is the writers room.
where. uh. Scotty's
hilarious monologues
and comedy bits are born.
The writers are waiting to hear
if their material
made the final cut.
-He hated it.
-[writers groan]
Monologue or the mayor bit?
All of it. Every line.
But we stayed late last
night. That was good stuff.
Are you sure you
pitched it right?
Yes. Ronan. I know how to pitch.
I come from a comedy background.
-Improv.
Look. he just didn't
like it. It happens.
Okay. but what kind
of mood was he in?
Because you also have to
pick the right moment.
Because it's our job
as women to always
ascertain a man's emotional
state before speaking.
Look. go ahead and blame
me. I'm used to it.
But the material isn't
going in the show.
And we know where it is going.
[shredder whirring]
Ugh. yes. the dulcet
tones of Mickey Two.
Okay. so. our stuff
went in the shredder.
What'll he use instead?
He's going to the packets.
-[all exclaiming] -For the love of comedy!
-Oh. no!
-This is your fault.
-Oh. no. come on!
-[all grumbling]
-Whose side are you on?
♪ ♪
Hi. Sheryl.
I'm Laurel. head writer.
executive producer of Way Late.
-Are you nervous?
-Oh. God.
is it that obvious?
It's just... network
television. [weak chuckle]
I'm old enough that
still means something.
[chuckles] Well. our
audience feels the same.
-Oh. [laughs] Okay.
-So. here are some questions
that Scotty may or may not ask.
Do you think that
he'll be nice to me?
I mean. I know sometimes he
can be a little bit acerbic...
That's a lie! I'm always nice.
Oh. my God! You're... so
much taller in person.
Well. that depends on
the size of your screen.
-Hi. Sheryl. Nice to meet you.
-Hi.
Hey. listen. it's
gonna be a lot of fun.
Just relax and be yourself.
I actually brought a
friend for support.
Elsbeth? Elsbeth!
What?! Oh. Hi! Yes. I'm here.
SHERYL: Uh. Elsbeth
was my journey partner
at one of the wellness centers
-I wrote about.
-SCOTTY: Hi. Elsbeth.
I hope I'm saying that right.
'cause I won't be
saying it again.
Oh. my gosh. it's you.
I can't believe it.
Oh. I am such a fan.
You're so tall.
Yeah. we established that
while you were unconscious.
Yeah... Oh. right.
Sorry. Um...
I came straight here
from the airport.
I was in Scotland
visiting Angus.
Uh. my boyfriend.
Uh. actually... I am not sure
I should call him
that. but. um. anyway.
I am jet-lagged. which is
why I seem a little loopy.
although some people think...
[laughs] I always
seem a little loopy.
You know what's fascinating
about that story?
I didn't ask.
-See you out there.
-SHERYL: Okay.
Uh. okay. Okay.
-Oh...
-You got this.
-Is there coffee?
-Yeah.
Get her a decaf!
[cheering. applause]
Hey. everybody. Welcome
back to Way Late.
We are talking to Sheryl Jacobs.
the author of Unwell on My Way.
So. Sheryl. it says in here that
you went from wellness
center to wellness center
for four full years.
Four years and three months.
You must have had a lot of
junk mail when you came home.
SHERYL: Oh.
[chuckles] Yeah. I...
I mentioned that in the book.
Didn't you read it?
Well. I have to read a
lot for this job. Sheryl.
Oh. right. Is that hard for you?
Mickey. Sheryl's
being mean to me.
Hey. did you meet Mickey Muntz?
Oh. no. but I-I know
him from the show.
MICKEY: Good to meet you.
Sheryl. I loved your book
-and I read every word of it.
-Oh...
Hey. uh. listen. let
me ask you something.
Uh. what wellness
treatment do you think
would be good for
Mickey over there?
I mean. obviously.
he needs all of 'em.
but what would you
start with first...
the weight or the
air of desperation?
SHERYL: Well. um.
I think focusing
on the. um. spiritual.
uh. being is always first.
and then the physical.
Well. that's good to know.
'cause we don't want to focus
on Mickey's physical being.
Yes. and my spirit
is definitely broken.
SCOTTY: Anyway. this has
been. uh. great. Sheryl.
Would you please come back?
SHERYL: Is that it?
-That's it.
-Um. sure...
-It is way late.
-♪
Go to sleep. everybody.
-Bye-bye.
-[cheering. applause]
Well?
-He said no.
-Are you kidding me?
Sweetheart.
Did you tell him
what the doctor said?
-I did.
-Word for word?
-Honey.
-[sighs] Mickey. your heart
is in bad shape. If
you don't get a break
from the stress... taking
his abuse every night...
who knows what could happen?
Look. you push me to get a
mammogram once a year. and I do.
and I love you for
taking care of me.
Now. I'm asking you to
take care of yourself.
He said it was impossible.
The ratings are down
and he's got Ronan
waiting in the wings
to take his place.
This is the job I signed up for.
God. he's killing you.
How dare he?
I'll be fine.
Look. we owe Scotty so much.
We'd be nothing without him.
Oh. I don't believe that.
No. you're right.
I'd be nothing without him.
I mean. you could be anything.
Oh. Mickey. You're
such a good person.
Yeah. but I wanted to
be in show business.
Get changed and go home.
I'm gonna watch the edit.
Not that they know I'm there.
What would you
start with first...
the weight or the
air of desperation?
-Bump me that close-up.
-Yep.
I figured he would send you.
He told you what
the doctors said?
[clicks tongue] Doctors?
Are we still doing doctors?
Scotty. this show is
literally killing him.
But we'll miss it
when it's gone.
[sighs] Yeah. yeah. I know.
This show is what the
three of us dreamed about.
-and we have to live with the choices that we made...
-Right.
-and you chose Mickey.
-I did.
Any regrets?
Only when I watch the show.
Cute. What about kids?
No. no. no. you were
right about that.
You know. we would have
never have gotten this far
if we had to split our focus.
Drink?
Uh... yeah.
I was thinking about
that night the scout came
from the network to see
our show for the first time
and someone from the audience
called out "Renaissance fair"
as a suggestion.
So we're walking
down memory lane now.
And you had that
Renaissance fair bit
from the week
before that killed.
It was ready to go. making
you look like a star.
[chuckles]
Now. the guy who called
it out was a plant. right?
Laurel. good luck
comes from preparation.
Yeah. You know. it's funny...
I think I chose Mickey
over you that night.
Your ambition scared
the hell out of me.
Gosh. what was I so afraid of?
[chuckles]
-Laurel.
-Mm-hmm?
-What are you doing?
-Just
making it look better.
you know? Sexier.
Are we...
Are we really gonna do this?
Doing what? I'm
just having a drink
with an old friend.
Don't you miss the way
it felt. before all this?
-Well. of course.
-Mm.
I mean. some nights. I...
look over at you and...
and I'm right back there.
the three of us on
stage. making it up
-as we go along. you know?
-Yeah.
So in tune with each other.
So young.
You haven't changed.
Come with me.
What-What's... Okay.
Yeah. all right.
No. I'm into it.
-Um... all right. yeah.
-Mm.
[elevator bell dings] -I've
been nothing but loyal to you.
and Laurel has. too.
Uh. and-and I deserve this.
My health is more
important than some show.
Look. Laurel. I just
want you to know
I've always
respected and admired
-how loyal you are to Mickey.
-I know.
But I guess. um...
even you have your limits.
Guess I do.
Aah! [grunting]
[crack]
Scotty. I can't do this anymore.
Scotty?
Scotty!
Was that a scream?
[mouthing]
Mom. I thought you weren't
supposed to be home
for another few days.
Did things with
Angus not go so well?
No. Sheryl asked me to
go to the show with her
and then to dinner. and I want
to be supportive of my friends.
especially now that Kaya's off
-working undercover. [chuckles]
-Are we sure that's the reason?
[gasps] There she is!
[gasps] Oh. my Gonzo!
I missed you so much.
-Were you a good girl?
-Easy peasy.
-Oh. Teddy. Teddy. I have gifts.
-Okay. Mom.
-let me. You're exhausted.
-Okay.
Thank you. sweetheart. Yeah.
the-the one on the top.
Yeah. that's for Gonzo.
-Yeah. There you go!
-[singsongy]: Oh!
-Go get it. girl!
-[chuckles]
And that's for you and Roy.
You got us tartan kilts.
Yeah. you both have
such nice calves.
Oh. thanks. That's fun.
Although...
I think it's probably
a little too soon
for me to wear
these at my new job.
Yeah. probably. Wait. what?
Teddy! You got a job?
-Shocking. I know.
-Oh!
Well. Roy and I were at this
bar and we met this reporter.
and I started going on about
how the truth has been devalued
and the world needs
more fact-checkers.
-Oh. that's so true.
-And before I knew it.
you know. I was hired
at The New York View.
Did you know one of
their journalists
got murdered with a cattle prod?
Mm-hmm. That's how we got Gonzo.
-What?
-Uh. long story.
Anyway. I really do think
that investigative journalism
could be the path for me.
Did you know that Chris Hayes
was a philosophy
major just like I was?
-I think I did know that.
-And the best part is that
print media is a dying business.
and so the bar to
entry is really low.
Mm. that's wonderful.
honey. I'm so...
-Okay. Mom. you need to sleep.
-Oh... Oh. gosh.
No! I want to stay up.
I have to watch Way Late.
I have to see if I see myself
-in the audience.
-[phone dings]
Um. Mom. I think the show
may be preempted.
Oh. no. What happened?
Is it Greenland?
[phone vibrates]
Oh. Hello?
Elsbeth. Oh. good.
you made it home.
And you're still awake.
♪ ♪
Oh. Captain Wagner.
Here I am. across
several time zones.
reporting for duty.
I'm glad you came back
early. I need you here.
Talk about a high-profile case.
Yeah. I see Detective Smullen.
Is there an officer assigned
to "keep me in line"?
Yes. you'll be working
with Officer Grace Hackett.
who's particularly
well-suited for this.
Oh. Why is that?
Well. I happen to
know she's a. uh.
stand-up comic in
her spare time.
Ooh. that ought to be
helpful. And good for laughs.
Where is she? Oh. I see. Um...
Hi. Officer Hackett? Hi.
Oh. gosh.
I'm sorry. I didn't realize
you were having a moment there.
No. [weak chuckle]
-I'm...
-Yeah. I-I know who you are.
I'm sorry.
I always dreamed of being here.
in this office. and. um...
this is just not the way
I wanted to get here.
-you know?
-Y-Yeah.
Oh. I'm sorry. I'm an empath.
That's okay.
It's nice.
According to Mickey Muntz.
our sidekick who found the body.
Scotty Bristol was
famous for feeding
material that he didn't like
into this industrial
monster over here
just to. uh. piss
off the writers.
-God. this business.
-BOBBY: Yeah.
We're bagging what's in
the bin for evidence.
but it's looking like
a pretty unfortunate
necktie shredding accident.
Were these his earbuds?
So we assume.
Do we know what he
was listening to?
Merrily We Roll Along.
original cast recording.
[soft chuckle] Your
guess is as good as mine.
Oh. I think my guess
is probably better.
Sondheim's score
is a masterpiece.
And the story is told backwards.
which always made
perfect sense to me.
Yeah. me too.
So...
he was strangled by his...
tie?
Mm. so that means his
back was to the shredder.
Why would that be?
Maybe he turned to get away.
Uh. well...
[imitates choking] Mm.
But his tie would have
had to be on tight.
otherwise he'd be able
to pull it off in time.
But Scotty always
loosened his tie
at the end of every show.
[deep voice]: "It's
way late. Go to sleep."
Yeah. that was a signature move.
ELSBETH [regular voice]:
Are there any prints?
Uh. none that we found so far.
Hmm. Ooh!
There's a "jam override" button.
That means the shredder
shuts off when it gets jammed
with too much paper or...
the body of a talk show
host. [imitates whoosh]
So. that means somebody
had to push that button
to keep it going. And. look...
there's a "reverse" button.
So...
[imitates choking]
...why didn't Scotty
just push that?
[imitates choking]
Reverse button?
Scotty never changed his mind.
Laurel. right?
We met in the green room.
I was here with
my friend Sheryl.
Oh. Jet lag.
Still got it. [chuckles]
Well. I'd really like to
take my husband home now.
He has a heart condition.
-Let's go.
-Oh. Of course. Uh. just...
Can I just ask on question?
Do you have any idea
what Scotty might
have been shredding?
Some material he
didn't like. probably?
-Let's go.
-Huh. That's...
odd.
Because Mickey said that Scotty
used the shredder to
torture the writers.
but the writers were
gone for the day.
weren't they? So the...
[imitates grinding. shredding]
...would be lost on them.
I-I guess we'll never
know what he was thinking.
He was here alone.
Or maybe not.
'Cause Scotty...
took out his earbuds.
but he didn't put
them back in the case.
as if he was expecting to
put them back in his ear
after some brief
interruption. like to. um...
talk to someone.
I really need to take him home.
-Oh. sure.
-Let's go. sweetheart.
Oh. and also... [laughs]
...these googly
eyes sure are fun.
[imitates roar. chuckles]
What's that about?
I couldn't tell you. Good night.
Night. Let's go.
It's true. No prints anywhere.
Somebody may have
wiped them down.
So this wasn't an unfortunate
necktie shredding accident?
I'll admit. Ms. Tascioni
makes some good points.
Well. that'll save time.
Elsbeth. what's your theory?
-[elevator bell dings]
-And that's for you.
[giggles]
I have gifts!
[laughs] Okay.
This is for you.
-You didn't have to do that.
-Oh. I wouldn't dream
of coming back from
overseas empty-handed.
Okay. Lt. Connor.
this had your name on it.
[exclaims softly]
Just right. Thank you. Elsbeth.
You are so welcome.
[chuckles] Oh. Captain Wagner.
I know how much you
love your whiskey.
Duty free. which I thought
was ironic for you.
Bannerdale 18. Very nice.
-Thank you. Elsbeth.
-You're welcome.
And Bobby... shortbread.
Oh. [chuckles]
Oh. Officer Hackett. obviously.
I didn't know you yet. but
I got a bunch of
these adorable erasers
that look like
hairy Highland coos.
That better be a kind of cow.
-There you go! There's one for you.
-WAGNER: Whoa!
-Ooh!
-Whoa. So. how's the jet lag?
You okay to work?
Oh. yes. yes. I just need
my first big cup of coffee.
Hey. we pay for coffee now?
We have continued
to look at ways
to follow new budget guidelines.
Which is his oh-so-polite
way of saying.
"We've got nothing for you
anymore. deal with it."
Well. I'm sure it's
not Lt. Connor's fault.
Huh. Yeah. Well...
he's the numbers guy.
It's true. I am.
Does anyone have a dollar?
Okay. I would put my
thoughts down on cards.
but. um...
there seem to be no more
cards in the supply closet.
which is fine because
I'm on the wait list
-for a Sharpie.
-How are those
numbers working out?
Clearly. this was
not an accident.
We agree. So. who
had it in for him?
Well. maybe Mickey didn't
just find the body.
I mean. the guy was
humiliated by Bristol
every night for years.
Wasn't that the bit?
The experience can
still feel real.
ELSBETH: I don't know.
Mickey seemed pretty broken up
over Scotty's death.
GRACE: Finished
putting all the papers
in the shredder back together.
It was like that
scene from Argo.
Mm. Yeah. that is the one thing
I remember from that movie.
And it won Best Picture.
Uh. what did you find?
Uh. it was a packet...
jokes submitted by
an aspiring writer
looking for a job on the show.
I actually submitted
a few myself.
You know. I swear they
used a joke of mine once.
they just changed
Pelosi to Beyoncé.
And they didn't give you
any money? Or credit?
Well. I believe the
contractual term is "bupkis."
Well. sounds like Scotty
Bristol must have pissed off
a lot of writers. Maybe
one of them wanted revenge.
Mm. not likely.
And why not?
Well. I mean. most
comedy writers
would take Scotty Bristol
stealing one of their jokes
as encouragement to keep going.
We're a sad bunch.
Well. what about the
writers on the show?
How do they feel about
Scotty stealing jokes
and feeding theirs
to a giant shredder?
Exactly.
We need to talk to them.
And if you look to your
right. you'll see the office
where our host. Scotty
Bristol. was found dead.
That must have
been hard for you.
You know. it was.
I know he had a
mixed reputation.
but Scotty was
always so nice to me.
He told me all about his
early days doing improv.
It's amazing what
people will tell a page.
He'd reminisce whenever I
went in to empty Mickey Two.
Mickey Two?
Oh. that's everybody's
nickname for the shredder.
It's kinda mean.
Did you always empty Mickey Two?
That's what Scotty wanted.
I'm the only
non-janitor with a key
to Scotty's and
Laurel's offices.
The two of them were touchy
about their shredders.
Maybe because Scotty
liked to steal material.
-This business.
-BOBBY: Well. what can you
tell us about Scotty
and the shredder?
Oh. Mickey Two? He liked to fire
it up to remind us who's boss.
That's a funny nickname
for a shredder. though.
Well. we named it Mickey Two.
like Audrey Two in Little Shop.
because just like
the real Mickey.
Scotty made it eat crap all day.
[writers snicker]
Did Laurel know the nickname?
Oh. yes. but she would never
laugh. because she's management.
Or maybe because you were all
making fun of her husband.
Well. that's the
sentimental version.
We found a writer's packet
in Scotty's shredder.
Duh. Of course you did.
BOBBY: Well. him
using that stuff
must have really burned
you guys up. huh?
He should have trusted
the professionals.
-Yeah.
-Yeah?
Did it make you
want to get even?
Wait.
We thought this was an accident.
Is this a murder investigation?
It had to be Ronan.
It's so obvious.
-[writers chortling]
-He wanted Scotty's job.
-Come on. he's the guy.
-Steph! Steph slept with Scotty
at the last season wrap party and
ever since then -JIM: Oh. that's true.
She became totally obsess...
-obsessive.
-Shut up. That is just stupid.
-Suspect.
-But I actually bet it was you that killed him.
-Wouldn't sleep with you. and I mostly...
-You guys...
Guys. stop!
This is not a bit.
You mind telling us where
you were last night?
Yes. I did two sets
at Mr. Titters...
club in the Village.
Oh. right. yes.
we were all there.
Both sets. cheering him on.
Really? All of you?
Both sets? Why?
Well. we were sucking
up to Ronan in case
he gets Scotty's
job. Which. now.
he will. because I
missed my moment.
So. congratulations.
-Very happy for you.
-Yeah.
They have video
cameras at Mr. Titters.
You can see the audience.
I'm sure we got filmed during
our good-natured heckling.
BOBBY: Well. we'll double-check.
'cause it does seem
awfully convenient.
I mean. you guys all
clearly had a problem
working for Scotty Bristol.
so maybe you all
worked together to murder
him and cover it up.
Detective. you
got to understand.
We're writers.
We would never do
anything to rock the boat.
It's true. This is a
hostile work environment.
but we are all so
grateful to have a job.
This business.
[kettle whistles]
Which one is that?
Uh. benazepril.
Uh. it's the. uh. ACE inhibitor.
They don't work if you
forget to take them.
Well. that's what
I've got you for.
Mickey...
why did you go back to
Scotty's office last night?
I told you to go home.
I was gonna give
him an ultimatum.
Either I get the time off
so I can take care of myself
or I quit.
I mean. it wasn't fair to me
or to you anymore.
I'd had it.
Then I never got the chance.
Oh.
Oh. Mickey.
Oh. I wish I'd known that.
[crying]
GRACE: What is he doing?
Looks like he's psyching
himself up for something.
Yeah.
To murder someone.
[chuckles] I almost
quit all the time.
I just never went
through with it.
Yeah. but this time
you didn't just quit.
You murdered Scotty
for making you
a laughingstock in
front of millions.
[blows raspberry] You
know nothing about comedy.
Geez. I get no respect.
Um. what about you?
Did you want Mickey to quit?
I wanted what was best
for Mickey. That's all.
This interview is over.
Mickey. go home and call
Edward. That's our lawyer.
Clearly. the police want to
waste their time focusing on
Scotty's best
friend in the world.
This is unbelievable.
We'll be in touch.
In the meantime. we'll
have another chat
with building security.
I'll catch up with you later.
Hey. Laurel. Laurel.
Um. I just want you to know
I think the police
have this wrong.
I don't think Mickey
could have done this.
-You're smart.
-The thing is. I would love it
if you would help
me figure this out
to clear your husband's name.
Would you be willing to do that?
[scoffs] How can I say no?
Oh. Great. [chuckles]
MATTHEW: 'Scuse me. Laurel.
Wow. boy.
-You have a tough job.
-How do you mean?
Well. the writers think
of you as management.
Well. they blame
everything on me.
That's how Scotty liked it.
Oh. and Scotty... doesn't
sound like he was an easy boss.
And then to watch what the
show was doing to your husband
every night? Laurel.
you juggle a lot.
Well. you juggle a lot. too. or
you wouldn't carry so many bags.
[laughs] True.
Although I don't have to
think about my husband. Ex.
Although he did just
narrowly escape disbarment.
Not sure how I feel about that.
I'm sorry. but I have
an awful lot to do.
Oh. of course. Um. what
are you working on?
We're preparing a
tribute show for Scotty.
Oh. And who knew him
better than you did?
Uh. by the way.
did Scotty also call
the shredder Mickey Two
or was that just the writers?
You knew all about that.
Right?
And yet you acted
like you didn't
when I asked you
about the... grr!
Googly eyes at the crime scene.
You taking about the
night of the accident?
You asked me and I said.
"I couldn't tell you."
I couldn't tell you because
Mickey was right there
and I didn't want
to hurt his feelings
or make him look
guilty. God forbid.
So. I couldn't tell you.
Wow. you're awfully
quick on your feet.
Must be my improv training.
Oh. right.
Carl. cue it up
to the beginning.
CARL: You got it.
-So cool.
-[band playing on screen]
Wow.
Oh. hey.
Is that you?
That's. uh. that's
Scotty and Mickey
and you. isn't it?
Yeah. we were in a group
called The Overalls.
Oh. that explains the outfits.
That is so fun.
You guys were a big
hit. weren't you?
[sighs]
We didn't know what we were.
We were just having fun
and making each other laugh.
Three kids in Seattle
just loving each other
and what we were doing.
That. of course. was
before the jealousy
and the deals and show business.
Mm. Before you knew that. uh.
Scotty would be the star?
Oh. we always knew that.
Boy. [clicks tongue]
I would love to
learn how to do that.
What. improv?
No. it's not much
of a thing anymore.
But it's such an
important skill.
And it would be so
useful in my work.
I could probably use it to
find Scotty's real killer.
LAUREL: T.
ELSBETH [growling]: U.
LAUREL: V.
ELSBETH [cheerful]: W!
X.
Y?!
Z.
-[laughs]
-Okay. All ri...
You see how we're
more connected now?
Yes. I do.
I feel like I can
almost read your mind.
Okay. let's try a
more advanced game.
All right. let's do
-Questions Only.
-Okay.
Now. everything you say must
be in the form of a question.
Mm-hmm. Ooh! Like Jeopardy!
Uh. yeah. Yeah. like Jeopardy!
Okay. and remember the first
rule of improv: "Yes. and."
You never deny what
the other person says
because it kills the scene.
You go along with it and
you add new information
so the scene builds.
-Oh. All right.
-Okay. yeah.
So. uh. let's start with
a place for the scene.
Uh... Ooh!
A Renaissance fair.
Hm. Well. what made
you come up with that?
Did you know that was a
bit we did in The Overalls?
Yes. and...
[deep voice]: I've done a
bunch of research on you.
[regular voice]: Was that good?
Yeah. well. we haven't
really started yet.
-Oh.
-Okay? So let's start now.
-Okay. Okay. Sorry. sorry.
-All right. [clears throat]
So. here we go. Um...
Is this your first time
at the Renaissance fair?
Uh...
[British accent]:
Does it look like
my first time. lassie?
Lassie? Okay. well. yes.
that was a question.
but it didn't add
new information.
So. what it did was
it threw the question
back on me. so now I'm
doing all the work.
-[regular accent]: Oh.
-Yeah.
Oh. I see. Gosh. yeah. I...
I tend to do that with people.
Okay. oh... L-Let... let
me try-let me try it again.
Okay. [clears throat]
Yes.
[British accent]: Do
you like my breeches?
Uh. okay. good.
Um. yes. I love them.
-and would you like to dance?
-Ooh!
Absolutely. I wouldst.
-Oh. we're dancing.
-And...
uh. but. um...
will your husband mind?
Mm. Okay.
"But" is okay if it
keeps adding information.
which you did. And yes. he will.
-Will you tell him?
-Yes.
but wouldst thou
secretly murder me first?
[regular accent]:
Did I do it wrong?
No. it's just a
little confusing.
with all the "wouldst's."
I really have to get
back to the edit.
-Oh. shoot. Are you sure?
-Yes.
And?
Yes. and that was
a very good start.
You're very quick
on your feet. too.
But you need more practice.
BOBBY: Didn't we
already see this?
ELSBETH: Oh. he's wearing
different clothes.
I wanted to test Mickey's
story. so I did some research.
There's a fan online
who's compiled
all the most humiliating
Mickey Muntz
moments on the show.
Oh. there were so many. The
lint suit. the snake tank.
And then I got the
security footage
from after those tapings.
Sure enough. half the time.
Mickey was in the elevator.
working himself up
to almost quit.
just like he said.
Which shows...
-He did it!
-He didn't do it.
Oh. come on. He did it!
-He absolutely did it.
-He di-he didn't do it.
-Come on. come on. Elsbeth.
-gimme a break.
-Ah. ah. ah. ah. ah. ah. ah!
-One at a time.
-Okay. Captain.
the security footage
clearly shows
a years-long process of Mickey
building up the courage
to murder Scotty.
Yes. and...
it shows a weak man
who would never hurt
the boss he worshipped.
-Why "yes. and"?
-What?
You just completely
contradicted me
but you started with "Yes. and."
Oh. it's better for the scene.
We're in a scene?
Seeing Mickey go
through all that
was painful to watch.
but it must have been even more
painful for his wife. Laurel.
especially given
Mickey's bad heart.
But everything you say
also points to Mickey.
and he found the body.
Yes. and it points
just as much to Laurel.
And why are you
carrying a waste basket?
To make a point. Hey! Connor.
-You see this?
-Garbage?
Yeah. the same garbage that's
been here for three days.
Yes. it has been necessary to
scale back trash collection.
Oh. no. no. do-don... don't
hide behind the passive voice.
I should be able to eat a
banana and not worry about
the peel sticking around
long enough to grow fuzz.
Are you gonna do
something about this?
Nope. Mmm.
What did Edward have to say?
Uh. he told me he's gonna
put me in touch with a lawyer
-who handles this sort of thing.
-When?
I-I don't know. Tomorrow. maybe.
Maybe? The police are
not fooling around.
Why didn't you tell them
that you wanted me to quit?
What... what-what
are you saying?
The police asked you
and you lied.
I didn't lie.
I told them I wanted
what was best for you.
and that's true. that's
always been true.
Laurel. were you in the
edit that whole time?
Don't do this. Mickey.
-You're just torturing
yourself -Oh...
and me.
You lied. You did
want me to quit.
I wanted you to get time off.
And now you have it.
And you can use it
to get better and
to do great things.
But without Scotty?
[panting] I...
Laurel. I...
Mi-Mickey? Mickey!
So. he couldn't bear the guilt
of killing Scotty Bristol
and his heart gave out.
huh? Is that about it?
Yes. and...
that's exactly what he told me
just before he died.
Think before you write.
Crossing something
out is a waste of ink.
[indistinct chatter]
-Captain Wagner.
-Mm?
Are you fully aware of
what's going on out there?
To what are you referring?
These budget cuts... they're
so arbitrary and absurd.
and everyone's taking
it out on Lt. Connor.
Yes. And?
Well. I have seen. recently.
what can happen when a person's
put in that position.
It's not fair and it
leads to bad things.
Part of being a good boss
is effectively delegating
responsibility.
Connor can handle it.
What about his feelings?
-Connor has feelings?
-Captain.
You know what else is
part of being a good boss?
Taking the blame when necessary.
-[knocking]
-You... Come.
The report's in.
Uh. Mickey Muntz
died of a catastrophic coronary.
No sign of foul play.
Okay. Case closed.
CAMERON: We have some of his
personal effects to return
to the widow. His
watch. uh. wedding ring.
Oh. I can take them
to her. If that helps.
Yeah. Thank you.
You aren't done. are you?
Cameron.
Have you heard anything
from our friend?
I'm not supposed to
say anything. Uh. d...
I can't believe that Kaya
wouldn't want me to know
she's okay. Oh! [gasps]
I said her name.
Are-are we not supposed
to be saying her name?
Uh. we both know her name.
-So. when...
-No. I. um...
So. I have spoken to her.
and she completed
training and has begun
her first undercover assignment.
And she sounds pretty
damn happy about it.
Oh. That's good.
Yes.
Tell her that there's a plushie
Loch Ness Monster
with her name on it.
-Okay. I'll let her know.
-Okay.
RONAN: And that concludes
our tribute to the
great Scotty Bristol.
In the meantime...
I just don't think I
should do the tie bit.
-[writers groan]
-It was Scotty's thing.
Are you gonna fight
me on everything?
Hi. Laurel.
Take a break. We'll
argue about this later.
Looking forward.
Your deal hasn't closed yet.
Surprised to see you here.
[sighs] We're reworking
the tribute show.
cutting out any trace of Mickey.
Oh. right. because
Mickey killed him.
You know you didn't
have to tell the police
that Mickey confessed. There's
still spousal privilege.
You could have kept his secret.
I know. But I couldn't
bear to see someone else
take the blame for
Scotty's murder.
Of course. [clicks tongue]
That makes total sense.
Thanks for bringing these.
You know. there's something else
I was wondering about.
-What's that?
-Well. Detective Smullen
thinks Mickey's heart gave out
because he couldn't bear
the secret guilt anymore.
But if he confessed to you.
then that burden was removed.
so why did he have
a heart attack?
I mean. exactly when
did Mickey confess...
was it before the
attack or during?
Because it certainly
couldn't have been after.
Mickey knew Scotty
was in love with me.
He thought we were having
an affair and I couldn't
convince him that we
weren't. That's why.
I see.
Wow.
You just added new information
in just the right spot.
So. um...
did anything ever happen
between you and Scotty. say.
in his office?
[scoffs] No.
No?
Not "Yes. and"?
No.
[chuckles softly]
Can I have your
attention. please?
I know things are tough.
And we've had to make some
painful adjustments.
But in case you haven't noticed.
that is happening all over.
And the work that we do
is too important
to focus on
petty inconveniences.
We will get through this
difficult time together.
But in the meantime.
if you have a complaint...
...you come to me.
Hey. this isn't my trash.
[sighs]
Very funny. Detective Smullen.
♪
[gasps] That's it.
[door opens. closes in distance]
[exhales]
I know you did it for him.
I'm sorry?
I'm sure you are.
About part of it.
anyway. I mean.
you didn't know that things
would turn out this way.
You and Mickey and Scotty...
you had a special bond.
just like the characters
in Merrily We Roll Along.
Scotty's favorite musical.
under appreciated until
the recent revival.
Is there a point to this?
Yes.
Because that bond
also gave you power
over each other.
And Scotty used that power
to control your lives.
like when he told
you not to have kids.
or when he wouldn't give Mickey
the break his doctors ordered.
Well... How do
you know all that?
It's amazing what
people will tell a page.
And Scotty told me a lot.
ELSBETH: Your plan was
to make it look like
an unfortunate
shredding accident.
I mean. after all.
Scotty loved to torture
the writers with the...
[imitates grinding] ...noise.
But there was no one
there to hear it.
And...
we pieced the shredded
pages back together.
It was a packet that had
no jokes used on
the show that night.
So why was Scotty shredding?
Well. I don't know.
I wasn't there.
Oh. see. now. that's
not good improv.
A better move
was when you tried to
pin the murder on Mickey
after he died. Except the killer
had to...
tighten Scotty's tie
and then lure him
over to the shredder
without any sign of a struggle.
Mickey couldn't have
done that. But you could.
using your 30 years of history
and a little alcohol... [laughs]
...to manipulate
Scotty into position.
[mock screaming]
Oh. this is ludicrous.
[scoffs] Yeah. maybe. But
it was a pretty good plan.
Until after the
murder. when you saw
that the shredder bin was empty.
thanks to Matthew the page.
I never forgot to
empty Mickey Two.
ELSBETH: It couldn't look like
an accident if there wasn't
shredded paper in the bin.
And you couldn't use Mickey
Two 'cause Scotty's body...
[imitates choking]
...was in the way.
So you ran back to your office.
you shredded the
latest packet...
[imitates shredding]
...and you brought that
and put it in Scotty's bin.
Detective Smullen tried
a similar trick on me.
which made me think of it.
For which I have apologized.
[scoffs weakly] Well. you
can't prove any of this.
Oh. actually. we can.
Because it turns out. uh...
[echoing on speakers]: no
two shredders are the same.
The width between the
blades on Mickey Two
was a quarter of an
inch further apart
than the blades on the
shredder in your office.
And only you and
Matthew the page
had keys to have access
both of the shredders.
But Matthew was
with the writers.
watching Ronan Gaines doing
standup at Mr. Titters.
I was sucking up.
ELSBETH: It had
to be you. Laurel.
[sighs]
You and Mickey and Scotty...
you were old friends.
Now two of you are dead.
I didn't kill Mickey.
Not directly. no.
Uh...
We had a good thing going.
Mm.
BOBBY: Ma'am. This way. please.
You really do know everything
that goes on around
here. don't you?
You could say that
and be correct.
Could you do me a favor?
Get your Way Late with Scotty
Bristol office supplies.
They don't want 'em anymore.
Too depressing. [chuckles]
-Thank you. Elsbeth.
-Mm.
But I'm still gonna
use my bagpipe stapler.
Thank you for bringing all that.
It should help calm things
down here for a while.
Of course.
But. uh. you know. the
box wasn't that big.
The trouble isn't just over.
I know.
Well. maybe you
should rethink things.
No.
That's not possible.
-Uh. but. I...
-Elsbeth.
it was either those cuts
or get rid of you.
And that is not
something I would entertain.
-Hey.
-Oh. hey.
Thanks for a fun time.
You actually inspired me.
-Really?
-In fact.
I submitted another
packet to Way Late
and Ronan Gaines bought
one of my jokes for $200.
Oh! He did?
-[laughs]: Yeah.
-That's so good. Oh. wow.
See? The top job
doesn't automatically
make someone a monster.
Oh. this business. [giggles]
-[chuckles]
-♪ ♪
RONAN [on laptop]: Okay. So. now
let's introduce
my new sidekick...
the only idiot willing to
take this humiliating job...
-Matthew the Way Late Page!
-[cheering. applause]
Thank you. sir. So
glad to be here. Ronan.
RONAN: We like to promote from
within. We don't like to pay you more.
and we haven't. but
glad you're aboard.
-MATTHEW: Can I get you anything?
-[audience laughs]
Captioning sponsored by CBS
and TOYOTA.
Captioned by Media Access
Group at WGBH access.wgbh.org